<?xml   version="1.0"   encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/Vault/P5/current/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?> <?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/Vault/P5/current/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"> <teiHeader>

                <fileDesc>
                         <titleStmt>
                                  <title > </title > <title></title>
                                  <author></author>
                          </titleStmt >
                         <publicationStmt>
                                    <p></p>
                          </publicationStmt>
                           <sourceDesc>
                                    <bibl></bibl>
                          </sourceDesc>
                </fileDesc>
                  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
        <head>Wallace Talks at Hopkins Amid Pickets, Supoorters</head>
        <p> <roleName>Governor</roleName> <persName ref="https://lccn.loc.gov/n82048664">George C. Wallace</persName> of
        <placeName>Alabama</placeName> spoke to an audience which showed mixed emo­tion at <placeName>Johns Hopkins University</placeName>
        last Saturday. He was a guest of the <orgName>Young Democratic Club</orgName> of Hopkins.</p>

<p>Outside Shriver Hall where the governor spoke
before a capacity audience, were some 50 pickets
from <placeName>Hopkins</placeName>, <placeName>Goucher</placeName>, and various local or­
ganizations. Some people were handing out
mimeographed attacks on the governor, and a
pamphlet supporing the civil rights bill.</p>

<p>Inside the auditorium there were more civil
rights advocates handing out leaflets that said
"Let’s greet Wallace in silence,” and asked the
audience not to applaud, boo, or react in any
way to the governor’s address.</p>

<p>When <persname>Governor Wallace</persname> walked out on the
stage, he was greeted by a round of applause
as about half the people there chose to disre­
gard the leaflets. His security men were scattered
throughout the auditorium, and reporters from the
local newspapers took their seats in the front
row. Flashbulbs exploded as the govemor walked
up to the microphone.</p>

<p>The governor opened his speech by stating that
he would like to present <quote>"a different image of
people in my part of the country than what you
read in the local press.”</quote> He first dispelled the
press-created image of the bigoted southerner
by pointing out that his administration has done
more to further the cause of racial equality than
any other administration in Alabama history.
He added that he had once served on the <placeName>Board
of Directors of Tuskegee Institute</placeName>, the world re­nouned
Negro college in Alabama, and that his
administration has donated over $700,000 to this private institution.</p>

<p>His administration had also undertaken the
most far-reaching school building program in the
state’s history, which includes 26 junior colleges
and trade schools for his rapidly industrializing
state: <quote>"By the middle of next year,”</quote> said the
governor, <quote>"every student in Alabama, regardless
of his race, will be within busdistanceof a junior
college or trade school.”</quote></p>

<p>He then began discussing the civil rights bill
( H. R 7152), a bill he described as "the gravest
political issue facing this country in years.” He
quoted two past presidents of the American Bar
Association who described the bill as "ten per
cent Civil Rights ninety per cent an extension
of the federal executive power created at the ex­
pense of individuals, states, and municipalities.”</p>

<p>He pointed out that he was not here to attack
personalities, but only to debate the issues. He
noted that his opponents have not come out with
any statements on the civil rights bill—the main
issue in the campaign, but instead have resorted
to character-assassination. "If the civil rights bill
is a good as they say it is,” asked the governor,
referring to the bill’s supporters "why won’t they
face me on statewide television and radio to debate
the issue?”</p>

<p>He added that according to the press, any­
body opposed to the bill is a racist, a bigot, is
prqudiced and immoral. "It’s the bill that’s im­
moral,” said the governor. "Whenever the fed­
eral government can tell you who to sell your
house to, and can jail you without a jury trial
if you fail to do what they tell you—that’s
immoral.”</p>
      </body>
     </text>
     </TEI>
